I'm gonna go by the plural now oh you're
alive I I'm in such a great space right
now life is amazing and I feel like it
started right before this last Friday I
just heard about game B for the first
time last Friday I was on a life call
and I stopped and meditated and came on
and went through a bunch of notes that I
had and since that time I have been
interacting with the game B people
jumping in the cafe who had the second
idea cafe the idea to reach out to
YouTube influencers in their own private
video like doing kind of a less than 2
minute appeal to people who have
influencers and I did one for Chris Omer
from SBS gay who I loved watching
he's a amazing man who interviews people
with various diagnosises I don't know
what he would call them and just like
sits with them and gets them to share
their story and you can't help but fall
in love with them and follow up with him
also and so I did one for him because I
would love to have him on his channel on
i-10 an idea cafe as well as any of the
previous guests or any new people who
fall into that same category of being
someone who has a diagnosis that maybe
is a is a greater challenge and for
other people but in no way limits their
humanity in no way limits their value
and worth on this planet and that is
what the idea Cafe is so I reached out
to him but he's also like hard to get
like they don't even comment section on
theirs because they got it taken away
which I did a previous video here
requesting they give it back requesting
that we make a space for people with
various health challenges to be able to
connect like our only social media
platform like 35 years um I also reached
out the other second video I did I went
on to them for was for JP Sears he's the
like spiritual comedian guy who does
like slightly sir cake ads satirical
commentary on like the spiritual
community but he's also a really
spiritual person and he's hilarious and
I love his videos he did one on social
justice or
okay like a year and a half ago January
2018 and I was just so perfect I was
like here's my five-step plan for like I
don't listen to people then I kept slugs
it I don't even know what it was five
simple enemas but watching that I really
wanted to reach out to him so I did it
on video with our own five-step plan for
the World Cafe and I tweeted it at him
and he just right before I went live
liked it it's like me I liked it because
I like my stuff that I want to go I want
the algorithm to pick up and he liked it
I'm like okay that I'm now gushing a
little bit yeah it is it's okay to gush
it's okay to be exactly what you are in
the moment and that is what the idea
Cafe is and even if that's all that ever
comes from it that like JP Sears liked
the the tweet that I I treated out him
it doesn't even matter like it's just
it's fun to reach out to the people who
who inspire me and ask them to come on
and it puts me in a space of being like
we're on the same level cuz everyone's
on the same level everyone gets to just
show up and be who they are and yes I'm
reaching out to the influencers who have
the viewers who have the the platform so
they can bring a bit of that and spread
a bit of that like in socialism in the
idea that we have to like take from the
top and give to everybody else which I
agree with there's a need for like that
costs you something right if you tack
somebody you're taking from them and
give you into everyone else Robin Hood
was stealing from the rich and give you
into the poor and yet influence is
something that it doesn't actually cost
you to share and so coming on and
bringing with you a small piece of your
100,000 or a million subscribers and we
are also sharing it because we're not
just having influencers on that's not
the point the point is to create a
platform where everybody is seen and
everybody is heard on the idea cafe and
that's starting about this is supposed
to be this is not supposed to be an FAQ
on the idea cafe but the idea Cafe is
the first project of together tech it's
a little confusing because I'm crowd
democracy on all the social media
platforms but the project is together
tech because it's
we're gonna create tech together we're
gonna own it together we're gonna vote
on what we want to fund and what we want
to go into that together and we're gonna
figure out together how to do that what
is the best process to co-create
technology with if what I have
envisioned isn't working we don't hold
on to it and stick with it work we just
have to give it another decade the idea
is as I've been living in the world and
going live and no one's viewing and no
one's like it looks like I'm not doing
anything like I keep putting these
projects out to my friends and family
he's like Facebook groups and like a few
people join and then I kind of dissipate
and go off because I'm like this isn't
inspiring me back this isn't fun this
feels like work and I know that if it
feels like work I'm not supposed to be
doing it because it my body falls asleep
my body is just like shut down that's
not that's not an alignment with your
bigger mission and the idea Cafe is and
this space the crowd democracy YouTube
channel that I announce the thing with
Monday that I wasn't gonna do a daily
video anymore and I'm not but I have
been talking to game B people and we're
going to be recording our conversations
about their projects and my project and
their questions of my question just
having a conversation and then deciding
whether or not we post that together so
that it you know if someone said
something they don't want it to go live
they don't feel not live it's not going
live whether we go from unlisted to
public I northern we go from private to
public and I just am so excited by
what's going on because I can do it like
there's so much that I felt I wasn't
capable of and all of the previous ones
I'm like like oh we just need people
that people would come and I'd be like I
don't know what to do with people like I
don't know how to coordinate a time that
works for all of us I need the people
coordinator and so a skill I'm lucky and
I don't even know how to word what I
need like that I'm like someone to get
people and I just show up that's what I
need and that is what the idea cafe is
like and what is needed to bring people
in I'm capable of doing in a very real
authentic way
I can reach out to people that are in my
network and ask come be part of this
like is this a question that inspires
you I have a tiny group of people to say
these people like the ideas there's like
seven of us and that those people will
occur regularly on the idea cafe and
more people will come well come on so
that if someone's watching they can see
not just me answering questions and
getting to know me but other people and
to see their humanity and see the beauty
in each individual person and yet the
last idea cafe had like I
Remzi who's at who the game beer doing
this very game be project of the global
reset which is also like a globe already
said he's like Jubilee that's that's
what we're doing we're having a global
Jubilee yeah that's actually very true
can't believe I didn't connect those two
yet cuz I dunno what did you believe is
that's my name I know I have idea crater
down there but my actual name is Julie
like on my person and so and then
atheist Husker up a periscope who I
watch when he's not talking about
atheism just because it's not my cup of
tea to talk about spirituality it's his
and oh no I love talk about spirituality
just not religion I do it that's not
done like yeah it's not my what I eat
until actually want to do but he's also
running for office in Texas and I love
listening to he's very intelligent well
articulated like I find some other
people I find her too wordy deadly I
don't know like I really like listen to
him talk and then a few people who I
like know in real life or have connected
with him and in books and it was like
it's so amazing because it's like my
safe space like I'm like here's people
I've talked to and connected with and
here's people who and how to create that
and how to like fumble through like in
the first one I think we were all
present on screen when someone was
talking and there is good and bad with
that because you can see people getting
distracted but you can also see people's
emotions and in the other one it was
like I was popping people up and down
which also like one person leaves with
like it's it's a little distracting on
the screen but also like I got to see
people's emotions cuz I can see them at
the bottom of my screen slightly more
it's like washed out like it's a I don't
knows a filter on it and
but I could see they're reacting to what
other people are saying I was reacting
to what other people say but no one can
see that and I'm like that's kind of
part of conversation I don't know how to
do both of those things to have somebody
on screen like when we have the idea
cafe platform it will be and this is
clearly just me talking about idea I
guess I know my house like why are we
doing technology plans change so
creating a like when the platform's
there the ideas we do show up when we
are present with each other and we're
listening to each other and it's not
streamed lives if you're getting
distracted it's you don't have to worry
about other people seeing that you don't
have to worry about like to try and not
be distracted because we're trying to
listen to each other we're trying to be
present and hear each other's stories to
see
to listen for our commonality and then
having that little conversation at the
end the last for like five minutes like
how do we bring this all together I just
see so much power in what we can do
together with a platform like that and
so that is what the idea cafe YouTube
channel is is gonna showcase yes it goes
live at 11:00 a.m. on Wednesdays and I
want that to continue and then I want it
to spread to other time periods but as
like my original vision two weeks ago
was that we'd have one question for the
week and people would would post like in
the comments section and although I
really want people to do that as well
people to who can't be part of the few
people on screen to share theirs if they
want to share it like we will I will I
will watch it especially when it's not
you know thousands of them I can't wait
for that to be the problem I can't wait
for it to be thousands of people but I
will watch people's videos commenting on
that week's question and sharing from
their heart and but I can see so much of
what we can do with a platform room
where you show up as you are have a
conversation around a meaningful
question and we the platform give you
people to talk to about that question
and we generate those questions together
so not everyone generates a question
otherwise it's gonna dissipate the
energy or not to be able to have an idea
cafe because it'll only be maybe one
other person to talk to about it and
maybe that is something we want to go
down the path of
but not until we have more people like
we want like one question a day so that
as the people are brought in to have a
conversation with that question it's our
common thread that like we all have
something to share on this question and
then as people join in we can branch out
into areas of interest of like here's a
question on climate change here's a
question on spirituality here's a
question on fashion I don't like
anything people want it's gonna tie them
together it's about sitting down seeing
somebody's humanity and seeing that we
have more in common than we have that
divides us and the things that divide us
the things that lead to our diversity
you're actually our most powerful I can
see someone has chat has a it's now
viewing if you'd like to ask any
question about the global operative feel
free I'm just going on a whatever
positive version of a rant is a spiel us
feel about the idea cafe because I had
this stuff that was talking about tech
and why we want technology and maybe I
could get into that a little bit but
like technology is so powerful but I've
been focusing on that like I've been
focusing on like what do you mean you
don't want your own cooperatively on the
social media platform like do you
understand everything it can do but it's
from a point of awesome multi charger so
I'm just gonna put this on the screen
cuz that's what we can do here it's
Russia and I love technology I also love
technology I mean I love the upside of
it and I dislike it scares me about the
downside of it the idea that somebody
else owns my data the idea that like it
can change an election like those kind
of things are somewhat scary I don't
want to live in a black mirror do you
know what black mary's faulty charger
it's like a youtube not youtube netflix
show that each episode is a standalone
kind of dystopian technological future
and so a lot of the ideas i've created
of like oh there's a there's a black
mirror on that one like one of the first
ones is like social currency like having
where you're like a one to five star
person and the problems that occur
within that I was like but there's also
positives that can occur and I think
China's going
something like that it has a lot of the
negative stuff lack Mir absolutely
showcases like if you are friends with
somebody who has a lower rating then
that brings down your rating and I don't
think we are one two five star people
but in different areas we are right it
like our ability to show up on time
could be on a rating scale and we could
help each other or show up on time our
ability to follow through on a
transaction might be on its own rating
scale and without making people wrong
for who they are we can have more
information to know who to trust to be
like okay well if you don't show up for
a transaction when we're supposed to be
exchanging goods for money I'm probably
not gonna be as likely to sell to you
and that is you know I think that helps
us build trust but it's not about one
person creating that it's about getting
you know thousands of people together
and and creating a system like that that
we want to have to interact with each
other and then as people want to come on
board it's voluntary right like we don't
go out and rate everybody else although
some of the technology absolutely go out
and rate other people like the imbd for
politicians of course this urine in
public I you're a politician we're gonna
be rating you the CEOs and how like
corrupt and horrible or good they are
what their corporation is actually doing
and how do we have those metrics
those are things we're gonna go out and
actually grade people on but currently
it's the other way around they're kind
of like keeping data on us and deciding
how to sell us more stuff if we can
harness the information on them we flip
the script like it's the masses have the
power and we've already seen that in a
lot of ways like Yelp going in and
giving somebody a low rating especially
when they're a mom-and-pop type business
can be devastating for them and a tech
in Russia we are testing small chips
implanted in people that's scary but I
mean if people are willing in China they
have face recognition which gives people
low credit scores for bad behavior yeah
yeah exactly and so I think there's like
scary that can happen with
technology and right now that that's why
we want to focus on creating a
technology cooperative is technology has
so much power a little too much power
that we daren't wheel in that are not
wielded in any way in the hands of the
people we're having it wielded against
us and so they like the top what four or
five companies on the stock exchange or
technology companies are like Amazon
Apple Facebook and I can only it's like
blaming the Seven Dwarves I always miss
one out Google Tennis Google Google and
they're gaining more and more power and
money and good on them they've given us
stuff that we really need there's a
reason they've like won the market but
we can create something that doesn't
have the downside and does have the
positive side we can create something
that we trust where we're not giving our
data to corporations so they can sell us
more that's destroying our planet
we can create it so that our data is
used to something to cure cancer and to
create a world that works for like uh
environmentally positive like you can
see what causes cancer we can see what
oceans in which rivers and our polluted
and act on it and so creating the
technology cooperative is what we need
to do like technology is is both very
powerful and yet it's only a technology
company at the same time like if we if
we run a technology company with
democracy that doesn't mean my life is a
democracy you don't get to choose what I
do with my life all were ever doing and
because we're only a technology company
that's run completely transparently
unless we all agree to go change your
law that's not what we're doing we're
not changing laws so we can't say well
this is illegal and this is legal and
this is like everyone has to follow this
all we can do is create a to ask what
would help we can't make drinking and
driving illegal but we can ask it on put
that up in a second chat box we can only
ask like what would why are you drinking
and driving and how can we help you stop
well because I'm addicted and I really
want to get home and I want well we can
create transportation that gets you home
you can be drunk you and or your car
gets home we could create that let's
like meet people where they are if we
don't want people driving drunk on the
road is it one example of something we
can do that's our infrastructure for
employment in technological solutions
um well idea cafe is one of the it's our
first project and it's what I can do
within my capacity but the truth is if
we
have if we have the ability if we have
the ability to have a small and I'll put
the you next a second if we have the
capacity to have a conversation with a
group of people it doesn't need to be
7.5 billion it's maybe never gonna be
7.5 billion but to have a conversation
with a thousand people to ask them for
their ideas and to upvote and downvote
what we want in an app what we want in a
in a platform and then create a beta
create something that works for most
people and have the way for people to
constantly say what would make it better
and participate in making it better
without like Henze like you need to make
it this way or i'm not using it it's if
we don't have the same power dynamics
that we have when we create it together
that we have with Google or with Walmart
or with anyone that is selling us
something and we have that distrust of
them which arises from the fact that
Bitcoin blockchain and permutation for
currency requires a physical wallet like
yeah I mean that is I don't think any of
the crypto currencies that are currently
out there right now I don't think are
going to be the solution for the futures
cryptocurrency needs or currency needs
if we have a currency needs I think we
will decide on what the like what gives
money I know this isn't really what
you're asking but what gives money value
is us agreeing that it's worth something
right us agreeing to use it in
transactions to sell for Bitcoin to
accept Bitcoin so Bitcoin has values one
of the first ones on the market but now
there's thousands of them which one's
going to emerge
none of them we will create we'll look
at what is positive and negative about
each one of them what we need to have in
one and then we will create it and when
we create it it'll be something we will
use internally so it already has value
and then as we want to use it externally
yes it'll have an exchange rate for
something on the you know outside but
that's the only reason Bitcoin really
hustle you anyways cuz it's exchangeable
for real money on the outside then you
have the issue of like speculation and
you know exchange yet so so creating one
ourselves is going to be something that
ends up happening I don't think it's day
one like it's not what we need to create
are the things we're currently using so
that Google can't strangle our traffic
so that Facebook can't decide to stop us
from having our own social media
platform that actually actually
disseminates proper information and
action access and those things you can't
create overnight if I recreated Facebook
even if I have the capability and the
money to do that no one's coming on
board so the idea is to create solutions
together that that we already have a
threshold and users who want so if we
had a million people come together be
like yes we want a cooperatively owns
don't hold and don't contain my data
social media platform and then a million
people are enough to start it because a
million people can interact with one
another in a very real way we don't need
your friends and family to come on board
for you to want to use our social media
platform there's already enough people
here to use it and so that's how we're
creating products is we're not creating
them and then hoping people come on
board and marketing them we're doing the
marketing beforehand and being like how
do we create this how do we fund it
together and so the first one because
it's the one I'm capable of doing within
my limitation is the idea of cafe which
is my other YouTube channel it's a
YouTube channel right now where people
can come and have a conversation around
a meaningful question because that's
gonna be the first platform we create
but what that looks like
is going to change based on how it
happens on YouTube like what do we need
in a conversation what works what
doesn't work and we'll be using existing
technology like our first beta isn't
gonna have streaming video that we own
it's gonna be using zoom it's gonna be
connecting people in a in a back room
that back room maybe the back ends it's
gonna say hey when are you available
this is where you show up to your to
your video conversation based on your
availability and what you want in a
conversation and then generate those
conversations as we figure out the kinks
and what works and what doesn't work for
creating our social media platform that
will be probably a million dollar
platform that but the first one will be
a few thousand dollars to create and I
don't have a few thousand dollars nor do
I want to create something that's gonna
be slightly broken and then break the
whole thing I want to bring people on
board so right now it is just a YouTube
channel we're
doing that using stream yard - and
YouTube to stream live on 11 a.m. on
Wednesdays I'm bringing people on to
answer a meaningful question and
showcase what a conversation looks like
at the same time I'm reaching out to
YouTube so I was talking about for
anyone going on YouTube people with more
influence people with millions or
million or behind I don't care I have 15
people so like you have a thousand
subscribers by l.b I don't need doesn't
matter because I'm not asking how many
do you have in order for there to be a
bar for you to be able to come on I'm
asking people who have influence to be
to bring to come and share their
influence because we're connecting to
everybody's social media platform
underneath so if we get celebrities on
then they bring with them their fans and
with them their subscribers and those
people are naturally gonna see other
people talking and want to connect with
them want to follow them on their
YouTube channels or on their Twitter or
just want to participate themselves and
so as the subscription and interest
grows and there's people who more people
who want to come on the idea cafe than
we have space or time for that's when we
launched the beta crowdfunding platform
of like yes and let's create this you
don't need to be live on YouTube you
don't need to have your video recorded
and see the world to see it it's a vote
showing up and being present for each
other and having a conversation and the
power that that generates because all
the social media platforms are created
in a way that you um like in one person
has the influence right and you are like
a fan of them as opposed to like let's
actually meet and see each other or it's
like yelling across the void at each
other and we're never gonna find common
grounds having a space to have a real
conversation around around a question is
our first clap our first project for a
reason because then behind the space to
have a conversation and through those
conversations all of the ideas for
future technology will naturally emerge
and with them emerging will also be a
lot of the time there will be the energy
and the expertise to actually create it
and the willingness to fund it right if
you have 10,000 people talking about
climate change and we generated an
amazing so someone comes up with
something and we're like oh my god
everyone needs to hear that
so then we make it so everyone and then
we're like who wants to put in a dollar
and all of a sudden we have you know
like don't you say 10,000 I guess we'd
only have $10,000 then but everyone puts
in ten dollars and we have $100,000 to
create this with and then you also have
10,000 people who co crew even if
they're not involved in the in the
codeine and in the like they don't
they're not part of the more like the
it's gonna funnel down it's gonna be
like okay well 10,000 people have the
conversation maybe maybe a thousand have
the the harvesting of that conversation
to see how that what was commonality and
that's what sparks the idea and then a
hundred of those people want to commit
themselves to work you know on it and
ten people end up actually working
full-time on it and then one person is
like super key so we're like filtering
down we're not saying that yes when
you'd have a conversation with 10,000
people unless 10,000 people want to be
part of that conversation ongoing
constantly you know we're we're creating
the tools to make it possible to
co-create on a massive scale in within
people's limitations like I don't like a
lot of the things that are coming out as
technology solutions because they're not
accessible to me you basically need to
know how to code you need to know how to
talk hacker in order to be part of them
I'm like I'm like I love open source we
will be open source but I can't
participate in open source I can't use I
can't even create am Wow
this open source platform or WordPress
I can't even create a WordPress website
I have someone creating me at WordPress
website from the Wix website that I was
able to create and so like I don't have
the technology skills but nor do a lot
of people if we can't meet the masses if
we can't create something that is better
than what they currently have we're not
gonna call in the masses if you have to
come on board with us because you care
about like we're only gonna draw in the
extreme leftists and the extreme
environmentalists we don't have a
movement we have to be able to meet like
if we need environmental policies to if
we need ninety percent of people to
recycle and ninety percent of people to
go vegan then we need to ask them why
they're not vegan and meet them where
they are we need to ask them why they're
not recycling and how to make
easier for them and that's not what's
happening right now we're just screaming
at people all right it's like the
world's burning and I get it the world
is burning but it's not helping people
get to where we need them to get to and
so we have to have a way to come a
conversation and that is what the idea
Cafe is and we'll be like it's a space
to have a conversation and then we
create the actual space that is not
contingent on YouTube and not a
live-streaming which is is a vulnerable
place to be to be like sharing from your
heart when your leg it's positive when
everyone's watching I can see the IDI
cafe moving forward in a way that me
sitting here talking about the global
cooperative has not yet and maybe will
never generate the the momentum that I
want it to in order to create the global
tech cooperative because people here
global tech cooperative they're like I
don't have anything to contribute
I don't know tech I don't know tech hug
be part of a conversation or they know
it so much that they're like well it's
gotta be cryptocurrency we'd better like
confuse the language and hacker size it
and I'm like look if you can't make it
accessible to the people it is not
accessible it has to be intellectually
accessible financially accessible like
it has to be not from day one it doesn't
necessarily mean that like everything we
do has to be able to be understood by
90% of the people but to if you if the
concept can't be understood eventually
in an easy way by 90% of people it's not
gonna be adopted and that's where I
think cryptocurrency is an issue I was
having these thoughts yesterday of like
I feel I understand cryptocurrency and
now if I understand blockchain enough
but I don't there's when people are
talking I'm like what are you talking
about like this is it's like oh I don't
know like they're like making their
language much more complex than it needs
to be and the other space I have felt
that in where I felt grossly inadequate
and having a conversation was when I was
in university about physics and I could
have an intellectual conversation about
about biology and I could even possibly
do it about chemistry even if it wasn't
quite because I understood the bonds of
chemistry if I couldn't have as deep of
a conversation but physics was like
vibrating strings and Schrodinger's cat
and other dimensions I'm like Tessa
racks folding up like I don't
it's not mine but but physics and this
is what I was playing with yesterday I'm
like physics is different because you're
understanding something that exists so
you can complex that up all you want and
get as geeked out as you want to get but
blockchain and crypto is trying to
create something new for people to come
on board with and if they can't make it
accessible it's never gonna happen we're
not gonna be using we're not gonna the
regular people aren't gonna choose to
use Bitcoin when they have regular
currency the only reason they choose to
use Bitcoin is because it's convergent
with regular currency and unless we can
make it accessible to them it's not
gonna happen
accessible would be like what let's look
at these currencies let's make them
accessible what is the difference
between them not speculating as to which
one's gonna make it big like which what
is the difference how do we create one
that we want to use and anyone can have
a conversation about that what what do
you want to use it for what is it you
what is that you want it to what
features do we wanted to have and maybe
not everyone can understand what
features occurrence you could have like
do we use it and it circulates should we
use it and it goes away yeah you know
they might not be able to stand the
ledger but it's like that you understand
that when you spend something you want
it to be able to go to the other person
automatically not have four weeks in
between hand we don't want six to eight
weeks shipping and delivery like we used
to have when I was a kid you could send
away for something we want instant three
day delivery on Amazon it's like we want
much more rapid response those things
people can communicate especially if we
ask it in the right way whereas the the
crypto world is like well we're gonna
create this amazing thing behind closed
doors and then they have to resell it to
everyone and they can't resell it
because they're not speaking their
language and so then you know there's
there's 10,000 crypto currencies all
competing against one another and
they're not gonna succeed Bitcoin might
succeed it's it's even falling the other
one aetherium cerium has a kind of a
cooler a cooler base and platform but
having like we are gonna create one and
that's what's gonna happen with most of
what we do is it's not about somebody
coming and creating the new the new
fancy thing that they're gonna make
billions and trillions of dollars that
that's game a that
is what's currently happening under
capitalism and there's a cost to us the
user and / commodity and there's a cost
to the planet and there's a cost to our
democracies and there's a cost to
everything that we don't even aren't
even fully aware of like even the people
creating it aren't fully aware of and
each new technology comes with its own
risk like you put in thousands of hours
or tens of thousands of dollars and
either succeeds or doesn't and if it
succeeds its bought one of the big guys
and if it fails then it goes into
non-existence and someone else comes and
creates the exact same idea with a
slightly different edge and also it
doesn't work because you don't have the
threshold of users we're already gonna
have the threshold of users if we have
10,000 people that we're creating
solutions for that's 10,000 people to
use the solution certain solutions will
not work with 10,000 people around the
globe a food delivery place is not going
to work with 10,000 people around the
globe but it would work with 10,000
local people and so and it might work
with a thousand local people so you
don't launch it in that city until you
have a thousand people put in a certain
amount of time money whatever the
franchise fee is like right it's gonna
cost you fifty thousand dollars to set
this up and set up a commercial kitchen
to do this to do that do you have that
you need a tiny group of people those
people can sign up and be much more
instrumental you need a larger group of
people to like brainstorm with you need
a larger group to fund it if you have
that yes it will launch in your city and
so creating and then other ones can be
launched right away are ones that when
you have ten thousand people globally
there's there's always different
thresholds of usability like are there
enough people who speak your language on
it are there enough people who care
about the subject you care about on it
are there enough people who are
available in the time zone or time
period when you're available and we're
gonna create for all those things like
the idea cafe is 11:00 a.m. on
Wednesdays
that's 2:00 a.m. for some people that's
not accessible but the idea Cafe
platform that we're creating will be a
24/7 conversation where you the
individual get to come on in any half an
hour increments and have a conversation
we assign you people to talk to you
about that question for that day and as
the numbers grow we can have more and
more questions we don't want a thousand
questions and a thousand people that's
not
doable but a thousand people answering
one question a day is very powerful and
it connects us and then when we have a
million people one question might not
it's not enough it's like we want to
have a bigger you know we want to be
having maybe I'm really interested in
legal issues as I want to figure out the
legal part of the cooperative or I want
to figure out the legal part of my life
whatever we can have more more nisha
niche focus because that's what we want
we want people to live their mission on
the planet into their genius and all
benefit from that unlike what is
currently happening where it's all but
to me it's all about competition it's
all about like what you come up with
idea and so you benefit from it you have
to sell it to the rest of us because
you're like feeding off of us and you're
also giving us like you're giving us
something or we wouldn't be giving you
money but if there is something broken
about that because it's killing our
planet but I get why it exists the fact
we want to see profit so we get
innovation but that means not only do
you need that for your idea but
everybody needs that for their idea and
then there's like the legal structure
and the insurance structure and
everything that has to prop that up
because we don't trust one another and
you might be lying and then you have to
be like when we create something
together it's in that like we are gonna
be less likely to sue zero chance of sue
me no of course not but we're gonna be
less likely to sue because we have like
it's how you like to explain the
difference if you go to a restaurant and
you get food poisoning you sue if you go
to a friend's house and you get food
poisoning you're probably gonna tell
your friend and you might never eat
there again but you're not gonna sue
them and so when we're creating
something if we're creating a product if
we're creating a service and we're
looking at the risk we're saying what is
the risk like how do we put food safety
into place for for food but then
something goes wrong we're looking at it
and figure out how to make it not wrong
go wrong again but we're not suing like
that's part of our like terms of
agreement right that like you didn't see
it either you know I don't know if you
know like there's these little things
called buckyballs they were little
magnetic balls actually have some that
aren't called mochi balls but they were
all over the place like ten years ago
maybe and and they're little magnets
that people can swallow and
you swallow two magnets it's very
destructive because they meet each other
in your body and they can kill you it's
like a slow-moving bullet how nobody
thought of that before it was on the
market and kids started swallowing it
it's like nobody at that table thought
of that nobody had a kid that happen to
have a magnet that they swallowed and
had to go to emergency room okay if
there been 10,000 of us putting that we
would have thought about that and we
wouldn't we would have been like do not
sell this to people who have children
and then if you bought it when you had
children it would be this is my friend
from periscope so you have the kiddo and
maybe it's just sue sue your own friends
he would be interesting to see over us
and it does happen it definitely happens
but it does it's like you have to what
what level of violence or what is the
word that you sue people for um neglect
I can't think of the word that's
somewhere in the back of my head you
would have to have a higher level of
negligence I think is the word that you
would sue for than you would for a
corporation or a for-profit company like
this food poisoning they're not trying
to food poison you but if you like went
to a friend's house they're like oh yeah
that steak story I left it out for 48
hours yeah you might sue them then cuz
you're like you did what your ridiculous
human why would you feed me that so it's
like a higher level of negligence and
we're building it into the system where
you're gonna be less likely to sue
because we all should have seen the risk
so we all chose to kind of take that
risk on and we're looking to make it
better like if you are now permanently
disabled because of something we did if
there's enough of us we can figure out
how to make your life okay
like we can figure out how to like make
it okay without needing to go through
the legal system and when we make your
life okay we're literally making
everybody's hopefully everybody's life
okay
based on whatever that that disability
is now right like you went blind well
we're now we're gonna make things that
help you to not go but like not we're
gonna look at why you went blind and
help people knock up wines but we're
also gonna look at like what would help
you live your best life from blindness
which would help everybody live their
best life not only people who would
happen to have blindness but also people
who whatever tech that technology is
like when voice-to-text a voice helps a
lot of people but isn't only that that's
making any sense an interesting concept
dimension because it's not accessible
you need a lawyer yeah
that's one of the things we will be we
will be recreating to the best of our
ability like there was a good life good
good remember it's called if The Good
Wife had to spin off about the lawyers
and one of the episodes was a asset that
one of the lawyers brothers created who
had been in jail and he created this
this app that helped people not sue the
jail but put in a complaint against the
jail which there is a process to do but
it's so arduous that you need a lawyer
and so that you need to contact a lawyer
which is really hard to do from jail and
costly and all these things so we
basically made an app that ran through
it it helped you and the other lawyers
basically bought it and put it on the
shelf cuz they were like you mean you're
putting us out of this like this not to
happen we want our hundreds of dollars
per hour but we wouldn't like we could
co-create that like that is an actual
idea we can co-create to help people in
prison get access to legal advice and
there are things out there that are like
that and we're putting in place like
this is not a lawyer this is not a
lawyer legally this is not law advice
but it's the best you can access for
free it's the best you can access for
very low cost and so it's better than no
lawyer it's maybe not as good as having
a lawyer but if that's spelled out and
in in an actual Terms of agreement way
that like is accessible and not least 15
pages of legalese documents but like hey
we're not a lawyer
don't pretend we're a lawyer this is
like don't come back at us later and be
like you gave us bad advice this is our
co-created law advice so it's the best
we have to give it's gonna be less than
a doctor we can do that with therapy
like so many people have mental health
in crisis and there's no therapy to go
to well we might not be able to offer as
good of advice as a therapist could
offer we might not be able to offer as
good of advice as a psychotic an write
you a prescription we might not be able
to do emergency care but having someone
to talk to is better than no one and
we're gonna have less people committing
suicide
so like something's better than nothing
and if we can make it legally okay and
so that is the power of our technology
companies like we're looking for ways so
like someone has I've had the person who
made me this necklace commit suicide and
he was one of my best friends
one of my I have the idea had a
conversation around a question in my
community and I remember what I asked it
was like something innocuous and it
ended up that this guy brought forward
his his stepson committed suicide a few
months ago I didn't know that ring
community together and I didn't know
that I'm like what can we do to help
people who are in that prices I'm a
repeating crisis I've never been
suicidal but being in mental health
crisis and being like I just want
someone to talk to and I called the
suicide line because it's the only
people available and they weren't
available I was like what do you mean
you're not available this is ridiculous
I know there's people out there if I
post it on my Facebook to my friends
somebody would contact me but I don't
want to that's vulnerable especially in
this moment it's too vulnerable how do
we co-create that with people who've
tried to commit suicide but people
who've lost people to suicide to say
what do you need in that moment and how
do we create it and then we already have
the people who are interested in both
being the people people reach out to in
co-creating a space of like okay well
now you know you're not gonna go and get
institutionalized because that's also
why people don't reach out like I've had
a horrific experience being
institutionalized and if I go forward
I'd rather be dead I'd rather be dead
than go through that again and they
don't have anywhere to go and they feel
so alone and they feel it's like okay
well what can we do for each other it
won't be perfect we'll still lose people
but better than what is currently there
and that's the idea for everything we
create like what are you doing for food
how much money are you spending how much
time how do we keep bringing that down
how do we create a system so that
everyone can find connection and then
keep making it better and better and
better and what's going wrong and how do
we fix it and what's not working for you
come tell us have a space to say what's
not working and then be matched up with
people who that's also not working for
and co-create a solution together I mean
there's just like an infinite idea for
the amount of technology we can create
to make our lives better apps to
co-parent with the person you just
divorced that like what's the conflict
and how do you deal with money you had
like this app is created for that how do
we create something that helps you eat
better how do we create something to
help spaces that are more accessible
because we all have varying degrees of
physical mental and emotional and
sensory needs and we need to know what's
out there and how does that co-create
with
we're creating a party in here so I want
to come and we need to make it work like
the idea of me creating technology
there's so many benefits creating it
together because there's as few apps as
possible on your phone and yet they do
as much as possible and it's done in a
way you can trust it and you get to own
your own data and see where it could be
used powerfully for your benefit and
society's benefit and have people
generate all of those ideas because they
don't have to go to work 40 80 hours a
week to provide for their families
because we figured that out together we
figured out how to bring the cost of
food down down down how to make it so
that there's a way for you even if
they're not working to access food to
access education to access shelter and
like every weekend crew co-create
solutions that work for us together
bypass our governments who are never
gonna do it they don't want us not to be
poor they don't want us not to be in
poverty because it's how they they can
control us and why would you go and work
if your government was giving you money
that's what ubi is that I love the idea
of our governments it's gonna be like
decades before they're gonna they agree
to implement it which will be way too
late we need we can create ubi ourselves
we cannot tax ourselves and then dole it
out to everyone that is not what we are
creating what we can create is okay if
we don't have access to jobs because
they've been outsourced and automated
what do we actually need as humans
what we need is humans is food clothing
shelter water energy intranet right like
those things we can create solutions for
not all at once but like what's out
there already how do we make it
accessible to us how do we make it
cheaper how do we make it our own if
they won't let us buy it from them and
we can recreate the means of production
as opposed to seizing the means of
production which is violent and we don't
own it and would probably shouldn't
seize it going in and seizing Amazon on
behalf of the workers it's like it's not
the workers property but the workers
could co-create a competing one and we
could choose whether we were gonna we
were gonna participate in that and then
we wouldn't if they can't compete with
Amazon and they can't they can't make a
cheaper better faster product and pay
themselves well
that would not work in the marketplace
but if the user we're the user decided
to create a user cooperative that that
got our needs met and bulk buy the items
we bought off of Amazon and delivered
them in a way that worked for us that
maybe wasn't twice for 24-hour delivery
because do we need 24-hour delivery but
sat down with the worker and we're like
what do you need to make what do we need
to do to make your life better that
isn't maybe paying you more per hour
because that like there's million of you
if we pay you well more per dollar more
per hour that's a million dollars per
hour we have to put into the system if
instead we make it so that it costs you
less to get to work what about if you
you know we have music like what is it
that makes it worth it for you and other
like music sound terrific No thank you
how do we make it diversified and and
working right like if one printer if one
group one factory workers want music and
other ones don't want music right so we
have two factories or two shifts these
ones have music these ones don't have
music how do we co-create how do we have
part of the factory of music part of the
factory that was it why are you here you
can ask whatever you want I don't know
how did you find us how did you find
here are you a subscriber we're creating
at the global tech cooperative that's
gonna solve all of our problems and the
current first project iteration is idea
cafe which is a whole different YouTube
channel and what I was going on about
for the first half cuz that's where we
actually start I have big ideas on how
everything how this makes a world that
works for everyone how we create
technology together and how that can
give everybody what they want to need
with this little impact on everybody
else as possible but it's big and
complex and so what we're starting with
is the platform for a conversation
because people can understand that and
people can participate in that and you
don't need to have a tech degree I don't
have a tech degree you don't need to
have anything beyond show up and express
who you are we've had two idea cafes so
far they're an 11 a.m. Pacific Standard
Time the same time I started this 45
minutes ago but on Wednesdays on the
idea cafe and the first one was started
on 9/11
by accident I was like we're gonna do
this on Wednesday isn't the first
Wednesday happens to be 911 so we shared
our 9/11 stories it was me and two
people one of whom I'd never met and one
of them happened to be in New York at
the time and shared her story it was
very powerful and my other friend was in
Greece and I was in Australia and we all
share their stories there was this like
connection of humanity roads like I've
known this person for almost a decade
I'm gonna say like seven years and I
didn't know her 9/11 story cuz it never
comes up why would we why don't we talk
about that and so I didn't know we had
that common L and he didn't you're both
traveling at the time yet she was in
Greece and she didn't speak Greek and I
was in Australia and I spoke English so
like that and then flying home after
right flying to a destination pre 9/11
and after destination post 9/11 is a
different experience we share and and
then this four other person who like
agreed to come on when it wasn't even
9/11 we weren't even going to talk about
that and then agreed to change the
question and she was in there and she
told this powerful story about being
there in a very actually positive way
and and then the next week we had a the
idea cafe because because we changed the
story to 9/11 I'm like I'm not asking
some like surface question that
I don't want to participate in so I
asked people I was like what is your
like positive mission of the future I
remember how I worded it but not that
exact way but like so I had someone who
I know has a positive vision he has he
also has a world-changing project called
common planet about our global debt
resets and this currency that is like
created by us working but then when you
spend it it goes out of existence I
really like his system actually even
though there's some issues I have with
it mainly that we hopefully like how do
we start it and also there's a few flaws
in like ableism and stuff in it but he
was on my friend of this guy know from
periscope if he is Husker who's running
for office in Texas was on and one of my
friends who does virtual reality in his
it was on and they all shared and then
my someone Lana who have had some
interaction with who shared her her
vision of a future and my vision of a
future a future that works for everyone
and so we've only had two and now I'm
reaching out to like YouTube influencers
but over those two weeks it has grown
like I can see this this YouTube channel
the one I'm on right now has 50
subscribe
I put up videos I don't edit them and
that's not really what YouTube is
designed for so I don't really gain
subscribers no one shares the content no
one comments the way that I want them to
like no one's gonna read watch this is
49 minutes right no one's gonna sit here
or watch it before tea they might watch
beats bits and pieces of it but it isn't
designed to work on YouTube's platform
what I am doing but I have to work with
the social media platforms I have
because it's what's available idea cafe
can work on YouTube and it can grow and
people can bring their influence and
share it amongst everyone else
voluntarily we're not forcing anyone to
come share their influence but as we get
people to have YouTube followers and
have Twitter followers come and bring
those people with them and we're having
people on you have no Twitter followers
and no YouTube people they're just
showing up and having a conversation
conversation we're showcasing the power
of a conversation and so thank you chat
box we haven't looked it up Bri what
does a beautiful future look like to you
and so it was it was it was fun like
it's I'm enjoying being part of the
conversation I've reached out I'm doing
a video a day I was doing a video a day
on here but I would just come on and
talk for five minutes and sometimes it
was good and sometimes it was which
is the point the point is for me to show
up to be like okay I don't maybe don't
have something to say but I need to keep
showing up and moving this idea forward
and I stopped doing those because I'm
like now I have the idea cafe where I'm
showing up to this for this I'm doing
this every week this Q&A is going to be
at 11 a.m. on Fridays people can come
and participate get a bit of a better
idea of the vision get involved if they
want to get involved in creating the
tech cooperative and like what part do
you want to play and how do we get you
to play that um so doesn't become a bit
like a board of director median staff
meeting me just showing up at the same
time every week but the idea cafe I
don't know if there it has a whole new
life because it's like it already has it
already has 12 subscribers it already
has people like who are bigger than I am
we have participated in it it already
has like people are like yes I get it
this vision I get I'm like what I'm like
global tech cooperative people glaze
over just like me they're like I want to
be on Facebook not discuss how we
recreated Facebook like I get it
what I'm saying is changing the world
creating a world that's the best for you
can be as easy as going on Facebook it
can be as easy as going and spending
four hours mindlessly liking
you can meet mindlessly liking and
creating a better world for it you'll be
like I like this logo not that like logo
I want to commune or like just sitting
and being present with people and having
a conversation you don't you feel
positive at the end of that you feel
better at the end of that even if what
you discussed was super like deep we
haven't yet to have that discussion on
TI cafe but like a deep sad conversation
you're still gonna feel like at least I
connected with people at least people
were there and president hurt me or you
get angry after there's somebody said
something to piss you off
it's like right let's figure that out
let's figure out what to do with that
energy and what so that'll be next next
question tomorrow's question that we
like figure out how we like if what we
don't want is social media as it
currently is because there's these
heightened these people with all the
influence and we just listen to them and
then when you're the new person on
Twitter it's really hard to find
influence to find followers to get those
and therefore it's hard to have an
interaction with people and what we can
create is something that isn't that that
is just show up and being who you are at
the table there is no hierarchy here
we're not asking questions that you need
to be an expert on I might ask some
questions on idea cafe like there's two
youtubers I'm gonna reach out to who
both have had brain tumors ones
experiencing it right now and the other
one has had them twice and they both did
not start their channels because of rain
tumors they both started them actually
to create things like create mechanical
things and create ones build everything
or creed everything and the other one is
I can promote her name is and your name
where she creates his stupid things she
has a TED talk about like crazy things
that are broken things that are like and
they both had brain tumors and I've had
brain tumors so like we might get
together and chat about brain tumors
that's not something that everybody
could participate in but nor does it
require you to be a neurosurgeon you
don't have to be a neurosurgeon to come
on board and have a conversation you
have to share your experience and other
people who you don't have chronic pain
or other people who like share an
experience that I have there
we can have a conversation around a
question because that is what the idea
Cafe is is having a powerful
conversation on video or voice around a
question or may each take turns sharing
and then we like share fur and we have a
small conversation afterwards of like
how was that for you and like when did
you get out of other people speaking and
we are gonna create the platform that
does that the connects you with people
you have a half an hour conversation
then if you want you those people
dissipated you have a new half an hour
conversation with new people you can
join what you can go to none you're
allowed to not participate you know also
allowed to go to like you could go to up
to 48 in a day but I highly suggest you
even sleeping a very important part of
life and so then the next day the ideas
of the idea with the idea Cafe is the
next day some people are gonna want to
harvest that question if it was a
powerful question if we were talking
about climate change number ideas that
were created that were like I want to
work on these you're gonna want to
create the next question and/or so some
people go on to the next question to
explore that further and other people
will be looking at and talking about the
conversation and if that sounds too
complex it won't be nobody like right
you wouldn't do what do you want it what
path do you want to take like it's like
which questions you want to answer today
we will match you up with people and
then where do you want to go
thanks Chapa I'm also gonna go stay on
the idea is these I'm glad there were
people on in interactions because I am
last week I think I was just talking to
myself there might have been one
comments I think you were here last week
chat BOTS and maybe one or two comments
but yeah the idea is I'm better at
answering questions about this than just
spewing forth my knowledge because it's
bit like it's like all of the different
projects all of what it gives to a
single person and what it like it's like
re-explaining capitalism to somebody
who's never experienced I can feel is Oh
like it's like well then and like we we
ship our to China and then we like
this is what happened they're like why
would you do that well because it's just
what happened to be created I can see
the bits and pieces of like why we want
to create a global tech cooperative and
what it does and what it gives us and
how we have the good without the bad
like a good of capitalism the
of communism without the horrific parts
of either of them and it's by creating
it together and some people don't see
that vision and that's totally fine
because we're going to create it from
the ground up so I don't just get a
country that we now run socialist I'm
like how do we feed the people
turns out we starve it is like no what
are we doing for food and how do we go
backwards and recreate it how do we run
an economy without governments because
governments are doing it but like we
don't if we have to go through them if
we have to get our new political parties
and get them elected and then we have to
run through the current system it is not
fast enough it is not fast enough even
if we had it tomorrow it's not fast
enough our governments are not designed
to do what we need them to do because
they have to create solutions that work
for everybody and we don't we have to
create solutions that work for us and
then in creating solutions that work for
us invite people who that solution works
for and they will come on board and also
bring their expertise and what we create
with technology is win-win solutions the
only people who don't win are the ones
who like well what I want this idea to
be mine and I onin people come and pay
me to use it great go use cap like go
use game a that is game a use it but if
what you want is is is access to goods
and services that make your life better
and you want to help co-create them or
not you don't have to help co-create
them but like allow people to co-create
them for you and with you and you want
to have access to like the ideas that
you generate and ideas that other people
generate and make them better together
that is what we're going to co-create so
when someone comes up with something
it's available to everyone
so you yes you might share your idea
that might have made you a million
dollars it might have if you made it in
the old an old system but you get all of
the other ideas too that would have
generated a million dollars and you
don't have to pay a million dollars for
them so like we do we do better together
and so if there isn't any further
question I'm gonna wrap this up to get
like two and a half minutes of allotted
time left I could do this all day
I do do this all day basically and
that's also the other thing I'm doing on
this channel which is I think I'm going
to start saying this a few times
is I will be coming on and doing like
five-minute videos not live but recorded
and then posted when people have
questions that are the same question
over and over again and I want to like
answer it and is somewhat succinct way
then I will come on and answer like just
that question and then I have people
scheduled that's three people scheduled
next week on Tuesday like this is
awesome who may or may not after we've
had the conversation be posted because
they it's so there's people in game B
who are coming and having a conversation
around this project their project we're
having a conversation and we're gonna
record it on YouTube but it's gonna be
unlisted it's gonna be private and then
we together will decide to be unlisted
do we make it private do we make it
public or do we delete it if it's made
public everyone will be able to see it
and if not the nipple exists in the
space it exists and whatever we've
decided on um and they've agreed to that
beforehand all three of them have agreed
to having it recorded on video and so
that is a powerful that will be content
that people can watch and I explained
this better when I'm with a person and
having a conversation and other people
are able to well I'm only doing like I
mean I would come on here on say every
day if it was actually moving this
forward I'm doing this once a week so on
and next Friday I'm still doing it even
though I'm going to the climate strike
as well so I'm gonna do this it might
not be an hour it might be half an hour
so that I can have a quick nap and then
go to the climate strike with my
daughter so she'll also be running
around because she's stayed home for the
school because we're striking that day
for the planet and and I will be honest
thing I forgot to do this part I keep
meaning to do this because I don't know
if other people see these after and they
come up um that's the question I'm
answering is what we what we actually do
and then like I said I'm scheduling the
conversations as we're available and
then they'll be they'll be published as
they're available but the only time you
know I'm coming on live is now if there
comes another iteration where I'm like I
gotta go live every day at Tuesday
because we I don't know what we would do
on that one thanks to you like this is
the people who wants to actually
participate in creating it this is the
Board of Directors meeting we're live on
Tuesdays and maybe there aren't
questions it's just whatever people are
more committed to making it actually
talking about moving it forward talking
about what our various
projects are what idea cafe is and how
we're moving it forward and we may do
that if there were people who would do
that right now I would pick a time we
would do that and so I don't know about
having a constant stream this is what
this is what I'm committed to is 11:00
a.m. Fridays here
11:00 a.m. Wednesdays on crowd this is
crowd democracy on idea cafe holding the
idea cafe and then I'm also having
conversations like I'm creating idea
cafes with other people that aren't at
11:00 Wednesday like as I reach out to
YouTube people they might not be
available love it on Wednesday so we're
having it at any time that works for
them around a question they want to have
and I will find or they will find other
people to join the idea cafe as well we
will record it and then post it as
opposed to having it go live you don't
add into description some info about
Facebook periscope in this description I
will I add it after I add it after the
fact but you're right I have this one
it's now live like it is actually saved
in stream yard and that it's a very good
something I can do within my means to do
to put my Facebook group which is kind
of a little cuz I've like three Facebook
groups of the crowd democracy page the
crowd democracy group and the hope cafe
that's now the idea cafe group all of
which are tiny and then I'm on periscope
and Twitter as a crowd democracy and so
I will that is a very good suggestion
and I will put that in the description
because it's something that this is it
holds this and it will go live with me
every every time there's also a way
which I can also put in for people to
join me here to actually be live with me
here so they could ask questions live
either on voice or on video depending on
what their comfort with because that
sometimes works better as well and that
can happen live that's what happens at
the idea cafe is people there live
joining me and then I add the man and
take them out as they're talking and so
I'm also working with technology that is
new but fairly intuitive I really like
street merit actually if you want to use
like an affiliate link and I can put in
but I get like it's very little nice
it's like I got the guy get $10 of
credit and I'm not using credit because
it's free but eventually it might cause
money to stay on here so it'd have been
on per minute into an hour and two
minutes it's been great chatting like
this is
with better than less than last time
that I was on there's more interaction
more people here I'm in a better space
after having been in game B for for a
week and experiencing that with people
um thank you thank you for joining and I
will if I don't see you sooner see you
next week Friday 11:00 a.m. Pacific
Standard Time
that's an hour from right now row an
hour before right now whatever that
isn't your time zone okay take care and
I will see you next week